# **DAVID ADAMS**

Ely, Cambridgeshire, UK E-mail: dra21@cam.ac.uk Mobile: 44+ (0)7503 680053

Portfolio: https://blue-lamassu.com/

GitHub: https://github.com/DavidBlueLamassu

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-adams-922022a1/

## PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a junior **Frontend Developer**. I recently began an internship with Caustaza Group Ltd and I am excited to have this opportunity to expand my skills and to work on creating engaging and user-friendly webpages. I have strong problem-solving, research and writing skills. I am strongly self-motivated and work well both independently and in a team.

## **SKILLS**

- React
- Tailwind CSS
- JavaScript
- iQuery
- Node
- Bootstrap
- Responsive Design
- CSS
- HTML
- Netlify
- GitHub
- VS Code
- Playground AI

# **CAREER HISTORY**

- Frontend Developer, Internship, Caustaza Group Ltd, September 2023-present
- Coding Bootcamp, Frontend Web Development, 2022-2023
- Film Extra, Extra People, 2022
- Proofreader (Short Term), Hays/UBS, 2018-2019
- Proofreader (Short Term), Ashbury Labelling, 2018
- Career Break to look after my father who was diagnosed with dementia, 2014-2019
- Research Associate, Darwin College Cambridge, 2011-2014

(Previous employment details available upon request.)

# WEB DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE

- Deployed 12 frontend applications on GitHub pages
- Deployed 3 React applications on Netlify
- Deployed 2 backend applications on GitHub
- 900 contributions on GitHub (https://github.com/DavidBlueLamassu)
- Completed 2 group projects using version control on GitHub

#### WEB DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE -- continued

- Completed 17 high-quality README documents using Markdown
- Write semantic HTML
- Write high-quality comments

# ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Academic research (History)
- Advanced writing skills, professional proofreading
- Published in an academic journal
- Presented 11 academic papers
- Given 40+ lectures
- French
- Latin
- Spanish

#### **TEAMWORK**

- Completed 2 group projects on GitHub, 2023
- Established an academic seminar series with other academics at University of Cambridge, 2007-2009
- Ran an international History conference at University of Cambridge with two other PhD students, 2001

## **EDUCATION**

- Coding Bootcamp, Frontend Web Development (2023): edX/Trilogy Education Services (Online Course). Completed with a mark of 98.5%.
- PhD, History, University of Cambridge (2002): Funded by the Social Sciences and Humanities Research Council of Canada (SSHRC).
- MA, History, Queen's University, Ontario, Canada (1998): Funded by scholarships from Queen's University.
- BA First Class Hons, History, Dalhousie University, Nova Scotia, Canada (1997): Funded by Scholarships from Dalhousie University; Awarded University Medal for Highest Marks in History.

#### **OTHER INTERESTS**

- Enjoy ballroom dancing and have been a member of the Cambridge Dancers' Club.
- Classical music, jazz, fine art, literature, acting, theatre, philosophy, art cinema.
- Board Games: Go, Othello, Settlers of Catan and Diplomacy, among others.
- Chess: Regularly practice on chess.com and lichess; have an estimated ELO of 1600-2000.